Finding aid for the Nathan Pritikin papers LSC.1628
UCLA Library Special Collections
Nathan Pritikin papers
1971-1988
UCLA Library Special Collections
Pritikin, Nathan
LSC.1628
52 Linear Feet (52 cartons, 1 oversize box)
Nathan Pritikin (1915-1985) developed patents in chemistry, physics and electronics, was the director of the Pritikin Longevity Center in Santa Monica, California, and chairman of the Pritikin Research Foundation (1976-85). The collection consists of correspondence, research materials, scrapbooks, published and unpublished writings, speech files, slides, photographs, film, videocassettes, and audiocassettes relating to Pritkin's career and the Pritikin Longevity Centers.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ilene Pritikin, 1990.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942336193606533
Biography
Pritikin was born on August 29, 1915 in Chicago, Illinois; attended University of Chicago, 1933-35; became an inventor, developing patents in chemistry, physics, and electronics in Chicago, Illinois and Santa Barbara, California; became director of the Pritikin Longevity Center, Santa Monica, California and chairman of the Pritikin Research Foundation, 1976-85; publications include The Pritikin program for diet and exercise (1979), The Pritikin permanent weight-loss manual (1981), and The Pritikin program (1983); he died on February 21, 1985.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, research materials, scrapbooks, published and unpublished writings, speech files, slides, photographs, film, videocassettes, and audiocassettes relating to the career of Nathan Pritikin and the Pritikin Longevity Centers. Also includes books by or about Pritikin, including Dr. Miles Robinson's manuscript, The Pritikin program.
Health reformers -- United States -- Archives.; Nutritionists -- United States -- Archives.; Pritikin, Nathan -- Archives
- Nathan Pritikin: Biography
  - Biography
    - Pritikin: The Man Who Healed America's Heart. (Box 1)
    - Ilene Pritikin's unpublished version of foreword for Pritikin: The Man Who Healed America's Heart. (Box 1)
    - Ilene Pritikin's notes for biographer Tom Monte. (Box 1)
    - Miles Robinson, M.D. (biographical material and eulogy). (Box 1)
    - Biographical article (never published) by Tim Johns, 1979. (Box 1)
    - Articles about Nathan by Tom Monte. (Box 1)
    - Proposed biographical films. (Box 1)
    - Biographical notes by brother, Albert Pritikin. (Box 1)
  - Biographical Information
    - Nathan's version of his life story, told to audiences. (Box 1)
    - Bibliography. (Box 1)
      General note
      (see also: Scientific Press Articles by Pritikin and/or staff - PRF file)
    - Directory questionnaires (Who's Who in America, etc.). (Box 1)
    - Curriculum vitae, etc. (Box 1)
  - Honors: Proposed Honors
    - UCLA: Proposed Chair. (Box 1)
    - Kirksville College of Osteopathic Medicine; Honorary Doctor of Science., (June 7, 1982) (Box 1)
    - Invitations to join organizations. (Box 1)
    - Other. (Box 1)
    - Posthumous, miscellaneous. (Box 1)
    - Posthumous: Jewish Sports Hall of Fame, (June 5, 1988). (Box 1)
  - Personal Life
    - Birth certificate. (Box 1)
    - Move from Chicago to Santa Barbara. (Box 1)
    - Family life. (Box 1)
    - Food Nathan ate. (Box 1)
  - Genealogy: Family Relations
    - Genealogy:
      - Nathan's mother. (Box 1)
      - Nathan's father. (Box 1)
      - Wife: Ilene Pritikin. (Box 1)
      - Son: Robert Pritikin. (Box 1)
      - Brother: Albert Pritikin. (Box 1)
      - Living relatives, distant. (Box 1)
      - Living relatives, close. (Box 1)
      - Roland Pritikin (distant relative). (Box 1)
  - Growing-up Years
    - School records. (Box 1)
    - Boy Scouts. (Box 1)
    - Boyhood interests. (Box 1)
  - Letters from Former Employees/Business Associates
    - [No further description available]. (Box 1)
  - Early Nutritional Activities
    (see also: Early Nutritional Career, Box no.4)
    - Water. (Box 1)
    - Pursuing nutritonal interest while at business. (Box 1)
    - Formulating foods. (Box 1)
  - His Views on His Work
    - Evaluation of his own work (and his dreams). (Box 1)
  - Personality
    - Nathan Pritikin humor. (Box 1)
    - Sentimentality. (Box 1)
    - Persistence. (Box 1)
    - Traits. (Box 1)
    - Doodles/Notes. (Box 1)
  - Philosophy; Social Views; Heroes
    - Visions. (Box 1)
    - Social views. (Box 1)
    - Philosophy. (Box 1)
    - Politics, political action. (Box 1)
    - Heroes. (Box 1)
    - World War II. (Box 1)
  - 65th Birthday:, August 29, 1980
    - 65th birthday: Longevity Center celebration. (Box 1)
    - Birthday cards. (Box 1)
  - Events Near End of Life/Media Reports on Death
    - Rumors concerning health. (Box 1)
    - Pacific Palisades Center: Grand Opening, (January 19, 1985). (Box 1)
  - Memorials
    (see also Box no.20)
    - PRF Memorial Newsletter, Center Post tribute. (Box 1)
    - Nathan Pritikin Hall:, August 29, 1986. (Box 1)
    - Personal papers; disposition. (Box 1)
    - Nathan Pritikin Library:, August 29, 1985. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous: Family, Business Associates, Professionals as of, September 22, 1983
    - Nathan Pritikin Library:, August 29, 1985. (Box 1)
- Nathan Pritikin: Earlier Businesses/and Patents
  - Patents: List of U.S./Foreign Patents
    - U.S. and foreign patents held by Pritikin. (Box 2)
  - Patents: Relating to Food/Health
    - Investigation of patents re food. (Box 2)
    - Blood treatment patients. (Box 2)
  - Patents: Miscellaneous Correspondence/Documents
    - Patents assigned to Intellux, Incorporated. (Box 2)
    - re Patent no.2,692,190 (method of making inlaid circuits). (Box 2)
    - re Patent no.2,849,583 (electrical resistor and method and (apparatus for producing resistors). (Box 2)
    - re Bendix Aviation Corporation royalties. (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence/documents. (Box 2)
  - Prior Businesses: An Overview
    - Local newspaper coverage. (Box 2)
    - Business cards. (Box 2)
    - Customers of Pritikin's companies. (Box 2)
    - Products: Intellux, Photronics, Renco. (Box 2)
    - Businesses considered. (Box 2)
    - Creditors, some of. (Box 2)
    - Emerging new career: Publicity in his business publications. (Box 2)
    - Early Income Tax forms/financial records. (Box 2)
  - Prior Businesses: Photography
    - Photography businesses: Business cards, miscellaneous. (Box 2)
    - Photography businesses: Records. (Box 2)
    - Photography businesses: Customers' correspondence. (Box 2)
  - Prior Businesses: Glass Products Company
    - Glass Products Company records. (Box 2)
  - Research and Development (Miscellaneous)
    - Technical article written by Nathan. (Box 2)
    - Technical challenges (a sampling of Pritikin's solutions). (Box 2)
    - Pritikin's inquiries re Technical challenges. (Box 2)
    - Direct Positive (original title of folder). (Box 2)
    - X-Ray grid experiments. (Box 2)
  - Resistor Development/Business: Miscellaneous
    - Producing the resistor. (Box 2)
    - Resistor test results. (Box 2)
    - Resistor: Technical problems. (Box 2)
    - Resistor contracts: Government. (Box 2)
  - Resistor Development/Business: Lawsuit, Pritikin vs. Weinstein
    - Pritikin vs. Weinstein. (Box 2)
- Nathan Pritikin: Personal Health: Research Studies Collected by N.P.
  - On His Personal Cancer
    - Latest (recent) leukemia file. (Box 3)
    - Robert Pritikin's early leukemia file. (Box 3)
      Scope and Contents note
      This box contains studies on leukemia that Nathan gathered to help him understand his disease. Some of the studies have Nathan's notes on them.
- Nathan Pritikin: Personal Health
  - Nathan's Autopsy
    - Autopsy report and New England Journal of Medicine article. (Box 4)
    - Posthumous physician correspondence. (Box 4)
    - Nathan's death: Services, Staff press release; letters. (Box 4)
    - Controversy concerning causes of regression of atherosclerosis in N.P. arteries: (Box 4)
      I. Literature search and analysis.
      II. Nutrition Today article and related correspondence.
    - Newspaper ad. (Box 4)
  - Personal Medical Treatment for Cancer: II (Albany, New York)
    - Pentastatin decision (studies in Nathan's files). (Box 4)
    - Treatment in Albany. (Box 4)
    - Personal mementos - Albany stay. (Box 4)
  - Personal Medical Treatment for Cancer: I
    - Early treatment at UCLA. (Box 4)
    - Virus treatment for leukemia. (Box 4)
    - Nathan's notes on his treatment and responses. (Box 4)
    - Monoclonal Antibody Therapy: Dr. Kenneth Foon/NIH; article in Blood. (Box 4)
    - Robert Oldham, M.D. - Monoclonal antibody therapy. (Box 4)
    - Interferon therapy at UCLA. (Box 4)
    - Blood transfusions at UCLA. (Box 4)
    - Diagnosis dispute. (Box 4)
    - Golde, Dr. David. (Box 4)
    - History of radiation (etiology ?). (Box 4)
  - Personal Study of His Cancer Condition
    - Dr. Gerry Dougher. (Box 4)
    - Personal mementos re Nathan's cancer. (Box 4)
    - Study of literature re his cancer. (Box 4)
      (See also: Box no.2)
  - Laboratory Test Results and Related Studies and Notes
    - Lab test results: I. (Box 4)
    - Lab test results: II. (Box 4)
    - Bone marrow and blood slides (Nathan's). (Box 4)
    - Studies (miscellaneous) in Nathan's personal medical problems files. (Box 4)
    - Notes (miscellaneous) in Nathan's personal medical problems files. (Box 4)
    - Photomicrograph showing abnormal elements in Nathan's blood and miscellaneous slides re his blood. (Box 4)
      (See bottom of box)
  - Personal Medical Treatment (Heart Disease Era)
    - Sansum Clinic. (Box 4)
    - Personal physicians: Letters and reports. (Box 4)
    - ECG/Treadmill tests. (Box 4)
    - Experimentation with personal diet and exercise program. (Box 4)
    - Jogging records. (Box 4)
    - Health biography. (Box 4)
  - Personal Miscellaneous Health Records and Study
    - Nail problem. (Box 4)
    - Foot problems. (Box 4)
    - Thyroid problem. (Box 4)
    - Dental. (Box 4)
    - Vision, hearing. (Box 4)
    - Biological age tests. (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous health problems and records. (Box 4)
- Early Nutritional Career
  - LFC Study; JAMA Announcement; Other Promotional Efforts
    - LFC Study: JAMA article. (Box 5)
    - LFC Study: Assistance sought - devising protocol. (Box 5)
    - LFC Study: Nathan's letters promoting physician participation. (Box 5)
  - LFC Study: "Spinoff" Studies/Inquiries
    - Insurance company policy holders. (Box 5)
    - City of Los Angeles study (police and firemen). (Box 5)
  - LFC Study: Non-Participating Inquiry Letters
    - Inquiry letters: A - Q. (Box 5)
    - Inquiry letters: R - Z. (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous - lay people. (Box 5)
    - Medical journals. (Box 5)
  - LFC Study: Participating Physicians
    - Form letters to inquiring and participating physicians. (Box 5)
    - LFC Study newsletters, case history reports. (Box 5)
    - LFC Study: Correspondence with participating physicians. (Box 5)
    - Evaluation of Study. (Box 5)
    - Physicians' kits and manuals. (Box 5)
  - LFC Study: Bio-Science Lab Reports
    - Bio-Science lab correspondence. (Box 5)
    - Data release forms. (Box 5)
    - Bio-Science lab reports. (Box 5)
  - Earliest Ties to Nutritional Groups: I. Longevity Foundation
    - Longevity Foundation: Nathan's influence re direction of activities. (Box 5)
    - Publication of "Live Longer Now." (Box 5)
    - Fund-raising for studies on Nathan's concepts. (Box 5)
  - Earliest Ties to Nutritional Groups: II. Alexander Poniatoff and Associated Groups
    - Foundation for Aging Research. (Box 5)
    - Alexander Poniatoff - general correspondence. (Box 5)
    - Hans Weber, Ph.D. - consultant to A. Poniatoff (Box 5)
      (See also LRI-PRF Advisors)
    - AMP Bio-Research Institute. (Box 5)
    - Alexander Poniatoff /Foundation for Nutrition & Stress Research. (Box 5)
  - Earliest Ties to Nutritional Groups: III. Miscellaneous
    - International Academy of Metabology & American Academy of Medical Preventics. (Box 5)
      (See: Speaking Engagements: 1974)
    - Southern California Aging Association. (Box 5)
  - Earliest Research
    - Culling world's literature on degenerative diseases. (Box 5)
      (See Box 68)
  - Earliest Consultations: I. Personal Contacts
    [Names Kept Confidential?]
    - C----. (Box 5)
    - J---- F----. (Box 5)
    - N---- L----. (Box 5)
    - B---- L----. (Box 5)
    - J---- and J---- M----. (Box 5)
    - B---- and M---- S----. (Box 5)
    - L---- O----. (Box 5)
  - Earliest Consultations: II. Personal Contacts
    - [No further description available]. (Box 5)
  - Early Study by Nathan of Nutritional Relationship to Degenerative Diseases
    - Sampling of earlier studies in files with Nathan's notes. (Box 5)
  - Early Correspondence re Health Interest
    - Stare, Dr. Frederick. (Box 5)
    - Research: General correspondence. (Box 5)
- Long Beach Study
  - Long Beach Study: Financing/Contributions
    - Contribution appeals (unsuccessful). (Box 6)
    - Financial contributor: Rockwell Employees Club. (Box 6)
      (See also: Major contributor file under Diseases, Diabetes, Kirsten Foundation)
    - Financial arrangements. (Box 6)
    - Expenses. (Box 6)
    - Supply contributors. (Box 6)
  - Long Beach Study: Organization
    - Baseline tests. (Box 6)
    - Angiograms. (Box 6)
    - Blood testing. (Box 6)
    - Dr. John Kern: Study input. (Box 6)
    - Relationship with V.A. Hospital. (Box 6)
    - Nathan's input. (Box 6)
    - Patient selection. (Box 6)
  - Long Beach Study: Diet Plan
    - [No further description available]. (Box 6)
  - Long Beach Study: Reports of Results
    - Correspondence/talk. (Box 6)
    - Angiogram results. (Box 6)
      (See also individual angiograms)
    - Robert Pritikin: Reports to Dr. Weidman. (Box 6)
    - Published or completed reports. (Box 6)
    - Preparation of data for summary of study results. (Box 6)
    - American Congress of Rehabilitation Medicine: November 19, 1975. (Box 6)
      (See also: Box no.10, Speaking Engagements)
  - Long Beach Study Patients: I. General, Miscellaneous
    - Nathan's summary letter to patients. (Box 6)
    - Patient records. (Box 6)
    - Dr. Stenn's patient: W---- (not part of study). (Box 6)
    - Patients of Dr. Wiedman (not part of study). (Box 6)
  - Long Beach Study Patients: II, A - K
    - A---- B----. (Box 6)
    - E---- B----. (Box 6)
    - K---- B----. (Box 6)
    - M---- C----. (Box 6)
    - G---- C----. (Box 6)
    - A---- F----. (Box 6)
    - S---- F.---- (Box 6)
    - C---- H----. (Box 6)
    - R---- H----. (Box 6)
    - W---- K----. (Box 6)
    - J---- K----. (Box 6)
  - Long Beach Study Patients: III, L - Z
    - R.K.M. (Box 6)
    - Ed N. (Box 6)
    - C---- Q---- and P.Q. (Box 6)
    - M---- & F---- S----. (Box 6)
    - I---- S----. (Box 6)
    - L---- S----. (Box 6)
    - B---- S----. (Box 6)
  - Long Beach Study: Public Interest
    - YMCA Committee allegations concerning Nathan's ethics. (Box 6)
    - Media interest in Long Beach Study. (Box 6)
    - Publicity from Long Beach Study. (Box 6)
    - Quaker Oats Company interest. (Box 6)
    - Rochester, New York: V.A. Hospital. (Box 6)
  - Long Beach Study: I, V.A. Hospital's Post-Study Investigation
    - Deposition of Dr. John Kern. (Box 6)
    - Investigator's memoranda concerning Dr. John Kern. (Box 6)
    - Kern's correspondence in investigator's file. (Box 6)
  - Long Beach Study: II, V.A. Hospital's Post-Study Investigation
    - Deposition of Nathan Pritikin. (Box 6)
    - Investigator's memoranda concerning Nathan Pritikin. (Box 6)
    - Dr. John Kern: Dissociation from Study; recent correspondence. (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 6)
  - Long Beach Study: Miles Robinson, M.D. investigates V.A. Hospital Conduct
    (See also file: Books Pritikin Planned to Publish but Didn't: Robinson Book, Box no.7)
    - Correspondence with Senator Cranston and other friendly officials re V.A. investigation. (Box 6)
    - Correspondence re Dr. John Kern. (Box 6)
    - Correspondence with Pritikin (Robinson investigation). (Box 6)
    - V.A. correspondence (Robinson investigation). (Box 6)
    - Wilbert Aranow, M.D. - V.A. Hospital official. (Box 6)
    - Washington Post article by Dr. Robinson on V.A. Hospital conduct. (Box 6)
- Nathan Pritikin: Writings/Talks
  - : Writing/Talks, n.d.
    - Short single topic articles or talks. (Box 7)
    - Notes, transcripts and outlines for talks. (Box 7)
    - Talk synopsis form. (Box 7)
    - All-day talks. (Box 7)
    - Lorne Greene: Voice instruction. (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1984
    - Miscellaneous: talks., 1984 (Box 7)
    - : PRF Sixth Annual Conference; Inaugural Dinner speech., April 28, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Chapter contribution to book by Ken Dychtwald (with Nan Smith). (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1983
    - Talk outline. (Box 7)
    - Writing. (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1982
    - Guest Editorial: Preventive Medicine. (Box 7)
    - Houstonian Foundation ()., January 22, 1982 (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1981
    - PRF: Fifth Annual Conference., 1981 (Box 7)
    - American Heart Association:, May 14, 1981. (Box 7)
    - The Experts' Answer Book. (Box 7)
    - Dietary aspects of weight control and degenerative diseases. (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1980
    - Talks. (Box 7)
    - Writings. (Box 7)
    - The Book of Predictions. (Box 7)
  - : Writing/Talks, 1979
    - [No further description available]. (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1978
    - Writings/Talks. (Box 7)
    - American Medical Writers Association. (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1977
    - [No further description available]. (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1976
    - Writings. (Box 7)
    - Journal of Applied Nutrition. (Box 7)
    - Lay Publications - Army. (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1975
    - Writings/Talks. (Box 7)
    - Debate with Dr. Carlton Fredericks. (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1974
    - [No further description available]. (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1973
    - [No further description available]. (Box 7)
  - : Writings/Talks, 1972-1971
    - [No further description available]. (Box 7)
- "Three Volumes": Original Writings
  - Nathan's Originals in His Writing
    - Foreword - Nathan's original. (Box 8)
    - Introduction. (Box 8)
    - Current therapy. (Box 8)
    - Exercise. (Box 8)
    - Hearing Loss. (Box 8)
    - Hypertension. (Box 8)
    - Sight. (Box 8)
    - Sickle-cell Anemia. (Box 8)
    - Recommendations. (Box 8)
    - Summary/Conclusion. (Box 8)
  - Foreword/Guide to Readers: Introduction
    - Original typed copy. (Box 8)
  - Atherosclerosis, Angina Pectoris, Hypertension
    - [No further description available]. (Box 8)
  - Sight
    (Original typed copy, paste-ups)
    - Sight (originals). (Box 8)
    - Sight (paste-ups). (Box 8)
  - Diabetes
    - Original typed copy. (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous Material
    - Atherosclerosis chapter - early version. (Box 8)
    - Table of Contents, vol.1-2. (Box 8)
  - Unbound Copies of Miscellaneous Chapters
    - Introduction. (Box 8)
    - vol.1 - Atherosclerosis. (Box 8)
    - vol.1 - Angina Pectoris. (Box 8)
    - vol.1 - Hypertension. (Box 8)
    - vol.2 - Miscellaneous Chapters (various versions). (Box 8)
    - vol.3 - Diabetes. (Box 8)
  - vol.1: Bound Book
    - [No further description available]. (Box 8)
  - vol.2: Bound Book
    - [No further description available]. (Box 8)
  - vol.3: Bound Book
    - [No further description available]. (Box 8)
  - Edited Version, October 1988
    - [No further description available]. (Box 8)
- References re "Three Volumes"
  - Master List by author; Lecture list by author. (Box 9)
  - Lecture references - Master list. (Box 9)
  - Volume references. (Box 9)
  - Angina Pectoris: A - Z. (Box 9)
  - Arthritis References: A - Z. (Box 9)
  - Atherosclerosis References: A - Z. (Box 9)
  - Cancer References: A - Z. (Box 9)
  - Diabetes References: A - Z. (Box 9)
- References re "Three Volumes": Original Card Index For Pritikin Home Research Library
  - References re "Pritikin Program for Diet and Exercise"
    - Exercise: A - Z. (Box 10)
    - Gallstones: A - Z. (Box 10)
    - Hearing: A - Z. (Box 10)
    - Hypertension: A - Z. (Box 10)
    - Recommendations: A - Z. (Box 10)
    - Sight and Sound: A - Z. (Box 10)
    - References 1. (Box 10)
    - References 2. (Box 10)
    - References 3. (Box 10)
    - References 4. (Box 10)
- Books By or About Nathan Pritikin
  - Nathan's Input in His Books
    - Intellectual input. (Box 11)
    - Dedications. (Box 11)
  - "Diet for Runners"
    - Runner's Book. (Box 11)
    - "Diet for Runners"; publicity. (Box 11)
  - "The Pritikin Promise"
    - Correspondence. (Box 11)
    - Best-seller list; publicity. (Box 11)
    - Books mailed. (Box 11)
  - "Restaurant Guide"
    - [No further description available]. (Box 11)
    - Book corrections. (Box 11)
  - "Pritikin Permanent Weight-Loss Manual"
    - Ads, best-seller lists. (Box 11)
    - Art. (Box 11)
    - Case histories. (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 11)
    - Publicity. (Box 11)
    - Weight-Loss book (New). (Box 11)
  - "Pritikin Program for Diet and Exercise": I
    - McGrady: Tapes and transcripts. (Box 11)
    - N.P. transcriptions for McGrady. (Box 11)
    - Patrick McGrady. (Box 11)
    - 600 and 1000 calorie diets - McGrady's book. (Box 11)
  - "Pritikin Program for Diet and Exercise": II
    - Permission to reproduce (from book). (Box 11)
    - Publicity, best-sellers list. (Box 11)
    - Bantam Books - paperback. (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous corrections. (Box 11)
    - Book mailed. (Box 11)
  - "Live Longer Now"
    - [No further description available]. (Box 11)
    - "Live Longer Now" and the Longevity Foundation. (Box 11)
      (See Box no.4 - Earliest ties to nutritional groups, Longevity Foundation)
  - Pritikin Books: Miscellaneous
    - Grosset & Dunlap correspondence. (Box 11)
    - Other publishers considered. (Box 11)
    - Foreign language editions. (Box 11)
    - Literary agents. (Box 11)
  - Books: Pritikin's Contributions to Others
    - Book of Prediction. (Box 11)
      (See also Box no.6, Pritikin: Writings and Talks, 1980)
    - "The Experts' Answer Book." (Box 11)
      (See also Box no.6, Pritikin: Writings and Talks, 1981)
    - Ken Dychtwald's: "Wellness and Health." (Box 11)
      (See Box no.6: Pritikin: Writings/Talks, 1984)
    - Denis Burkitt's High Fiber Cookbook. (Box 11)
    - Victor Glenn. (Box 11)
    - Maury Dean - Guide to Nutrition for Young People. (Box 11)
    - Joe D. Goldstritch. (Box 11)
    - Ross Horne. (Box 11)
      (See also Box no.29)
    - Jon Leonard. (Box 11)
    - Trowell & Burkitt: Western Diseases. (Box 11)
    - Morton Walker. (Box 11)
    - Margot Siegel. (Box 11)
    - Dr. Anthony Satillaro. (Box 11)
    - Ellen Stern. (Box 11)
    - Book endorsements, etc. (Box 11)
  - Books: Unpublished
    - Correspondence re Miles Robinson, M.D. book with publishers. (Box 11)
    - Correspondence re Robinson book with Nathan. (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 11)
    - "The Challenge" by Miles Robinson, M.D., Manuscript. (Box 11)
    - "The Pritikin Program" by Miles Robinson, M.D. (Box 11)
    - "The Longevity Center of Santa Barbara: Does its Research Merit a Federal Grant?" by Miles Robinson, M.D. (Box 11)
  - Books: Unpublished, Miscellaneous
    - Proposed contributions to books by others. (Box 11)
    - Robin Hur: Pritikin-sponsored book on economic implications of Dietary Lifestyle. (Box 11)
    - Possible books in future - Simon & Schuster. (Box 11)
    - Technical books on diabetes and other diseases for medical professionals. (Box 11)
    - Material for books on nutrition for all ages. (Box 11)
    - New exercise book. (Box 11)
    - John Fried - biography of Nathan. (Box 11)
    - Donald Monkerud (Box 11)